<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description>A food blog.</description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 20:11:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Spinach and Feta Galette</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/spinach-and-feta-galette/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a video by a new-to-me food youtuber, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdTLhjAGVI_XDAuXrobtI6Q"&gt;Helen Rennie&lt;/a&gt;, for a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YJn1jBlC2w8"&gt;Spinach and Feta Pie with Pizza Dough&lt;/a&gt;.
I really liked the idea of making a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galette"&gt;galette&lt;/a&gt; (laziest/best way to make pie) with a no-knead pizza dough rather than a fiddly pie dough.
You mix up a pizza dough until it just comes together and then let it cold ferment 1-4 days in the fridge to develop gluten and flavor.
The process makes the dough extremely easy to shape later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real star of the show was the filling.
Helen's suggestion to use all sorts of herbs really improves on the standard spinach pie formula.
Spinach and feta alone, while it provides a nice earthiness, is too one note for me.
So, the extra accents that the herbs provided are crucial.
I added parsley, green onions, and a dash of dried tarragon.
I couldn't get fresh dill on short notice, but I would have loved to add that as well.
I also coerced my roommate into making his favorite &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OOkL5d8t1sM"&gt;tzatziki&lt;/a&gt; to contribute to the meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did have a small issue with the technique presented in the video.
My tongs are not silicone tipped, so they ripped the parchment that had become brittle in the oven.
I wonder if a silicone mat might have worked better or if it would not have survived those temperatures directly on the oven rack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://maxb2.github.io/food/images/spinach-feta-galette.jpg" width="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>feta</category><category>galette</category><category>herbs</category><category>pie</category><category>pizza</category><category>spinach</category><category>tarragon</category><category>tzatziki</category><category>youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/spinach-and-feta-galette/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 18:06:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Carrot Cake Jam and Cheesecake</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/carrot-cake-jam-and-cheesecake/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I visited my family recently for Easter.
We cook a big meal with a ham and multiple soup options.
My sister and I requested extra vegetables for crudités.
We ended up getting too much and I brought home &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of carrots.
I was searching for a carrot cake recipe and stumbled across a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/carrot-cake-conserve-recipe"&gt;carrot cake conserve recipe&lt;/a&gt;.
I decided to make it because it was weird and I still had some commercial pectin that I was too scared to use in my &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/sous-vide-raspberry-hibiscus-cheesecake/"&gt;raspberry hibiscus jam&lt;/a&gt;.
I had reservations on using pineapple, but it turned out really well.
It doesn't taste too much of any of the fruit included and truly does taste like carrot cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I combined this jam with my favorite &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/sous-vide-raspberry-hibiscus-cheesecake/"&gt;sous vide cheesecake recipe&lt;/a&gt; to make carrot cheesecake.
Instead of using graham crackers, I just sprinkled chopped walnuts on top.
I like the cheesecake a lot, but my favorite way to eat the jam is on a bagel with cream cheese and walnuts.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cake</category><category>carrot</category><category>cheesecake</category><category>jam</category><category>pectin</category><category>preserves</category><category>raisin</category><category>sous-vide</category><category>walnut</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/carrot-cake-jam-and-cheesecake/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 18:03:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Schmaltz, Garlic Confit, and Matzo Ball Soup</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/schmaltz-garlic-confit-and-matzo-ball-soup/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;As previously mentioned, I like to buy whole chickens, break them down my self, and use the carcasses to make homemade stock.
However, this means I also have a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of chicken skin saved up as well.
I had 3 quart bags filled with skin and decided something needed to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the only thing I can really think to do with lots of chicken skin is to render out the fat, otherwise known as schmaltz.
Making schmaltz is pretty easy, just combine the skin with some water to start the rendering process and continue to cook until the fat is all rendered out.
I chopped the skin into smaller pieces to aid the rendering and was the most time consuming part.
Optionally, you can add some diced onion near the end to add some flavor. 
I ended up getting 1.5 pints of schmaltz from all that skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I made was confit garlic.
I packed a bunch of garlic cloves in a mason jar with the schmaltz and cooked it with an immersion circulator (sous vide) at 190F until lightly golden brown (about 6 hours).
The garlic cloves turn jammy and can be used as a savory spread.
I took it to a family gathering and added it to mashed potatos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I made was &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/the-best-matzo-balls-recipe"&gt;Matzo Ball Soup&lt;/a&gt; with some homemade stock and off the shelf matzo meal.
The schmaltz is added to the matzo balls for tenderness and flavor.
It reminded me of a chicken noodle soup with dumplings instead of noodles.
I also added extra dill because it's one of my favorite herbs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/schmaltz-garlic-confit-and-matzo-ball-soup/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 02:12:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Charcuterie and Cutting Boards</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/charcuterie-and-cutting-boards/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had a work retreat this week. 
The second half of the day was a fun activity where we made our own cutting boards at a woodworking studio.
It was a lot of fun as my whole team is made of creative people. 
I also used to do a lot of woodworking when I was younger and it was nice to return to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made some standard edge grain cutting boards that you might see sold by an artist at a Farmer's market. 
The one thing that &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; surprised me was that during gluing the boards were only clamped for 30 minutes.
The leader of the class made the process really time efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward, a lady came and taught us how to make a charcuterie arangement on the boards we just made.
It was a fun time of drinking and making food art.
However, my salami rose looked more like a sombrero, so I decorated it as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://maxb2.github.io/food/images/charcuterie-board.jpg" width="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/charcuterie-and-cutting-boards/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 02:09:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chili Crisp Factory</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chili-crisp-factory/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I got a bunch of friends together to make chili crisp with me because they all love it and I'm tired of doing it all in my own.
It presented a couple challenges though.
First, I decided to make a double recipe and split it three ways.
There are lot's of respiratory irritants (chili powder and sliced shallots) in this recipe so there was constant coughing, sneezing, and crying (In retrospect, not the best idea to do with friends).
We were also cooking at my friend's house rather than my kitchen.
This was only a minor challenge in that I was in charge but unfamiliar with the equipment which led to some last second scrambling.
And lastly, we started at 8PM which was a big mistake. We didn't finish until 11:30PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was still a lot of fun and we all got something to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chili</category><category>crisp</category><category>factory</category><category>spicy</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chili-crisp-factory/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:45:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sous Vide Raspberry Hibiscus Cheesecake</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/sous-vide-raspberry-hibiscus-cheesecake/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I was sick last week which prompted me to take stock of my tea collection.
I noticed that I had a bunch of raspberry hibiscus tea that had been just sitting around for a long time. 
I didn't like it enough to drink 20 cups in quick succession, so I decided to experiment with it.
After some reading, I landed on the idea of making jam. 
I bought some commercial pectin expecting to use the manufacturer's recipe, but the amount of sugar required (7 cups!) was terrifying. 
So, I read a bunch of articles on natural jam making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main issue is that raspberries are a low pectin fruit, which means I would have a difficult time gettinga properly set jam. 
I also learned that citrus fruits are critical in jam making both for the acid balancing sweetness and for the large amounts of pectin in their rinds.
In the end I made about a quart of raspberry hibiscus tea, boiled that down for a while, added a pound of frozen raspberries, the juice and rind of a lemon cut into strips, and sugar equal to 60% of the weight of fruit. 
I continued to cook the jam with the intention of hitting 220°F, the temparature at which certain pectins need to reach to form a gel.
However, I pulled my jam while still at 212°F because it was already a thick jammy texture in the pot and I was afraid of burning it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final product tastes a bit more of hibiscus than raspberry and has a hint of bitterness from the lemon rinds. 
I think it's quite a good combination.
The texture is perfect as well, and I was really glad that I could avoid the commercial pectin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eating jam by itself is a bit crazy so I combined it with my favorite way to make cheesecake, &lt;a href="https://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/alton-brown/ic-mini-cheesecakes-7297817"&gt;Immersion Circulator Mini Cheesecakes&lt;/a&gt;.
The method produces perfectly portioned little mason jars of very light, airy cheesecake.
I don't make the Graham cracker crumble in the recipe, instead using the crackers to scoop the cheesecake out of the jars.
It's less work and more fun.
At the very end of mixing, I added some jam and mixed it just enough to provide some streaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a fun project to use up some of my pantry items so they aren't wasting space or being thrown out.
The commercial pectin has a recipe for "freezer jelly" where you just mix the pectin and fruit juice and leave it to set in the freezer.
I want to try this with some other teas that I have lying around.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cheesecake</category><category>graham-cracker</category><category>hibiscus</category><category>jam</category><category>lemon</category><category>pectin</category><category>raspberry</category><category>sous-vide</category><category>sousvide</category><category>tea</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/sous-vide-raspberry-hibiscus-cheesecake/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 20:27:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Buttermilk Brined Fried Chicken and Biscuits</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/buttermilk-brined-fried-chicken-and-biscuits/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My roommate recently watched J. Kenji Lopez-Alt's &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n5nKYqvu29w"&gt;video on buttermilk brined fried ckicken&lt;/a&gt; which is &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/the-food-lab-southern-fried-chicken-recipe"&gt;adapted from his book&lt;/a&gt;.
He offered to cook everything if I broke down the whole chicken. 
I really enjoy breaking down whole chickens so that I can save the carcass for stock.
I even asked for a nice boning knife one Christmas solely for processing whole chicken and fish.
There is one oddity in this recipe in which you leave the plate attached, but cut the breast in half the short way resulting in 4 square-ish pieces. 
In my case, the tenderloin separated from the breast and the plate which made it very awkward to fry. 
We ended up with a couple tenderloin nuggets because of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also made &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/light-and-fluffy-biscuit-recipe"&gt;yogurt biscuits&lt;/a&gt; with the leftover buttermilk.
Ironically, this recipe was originally developed to replace buttermilk with yogurt.
My biscuits came out a bit dense. I imagine that the pH balance was off due to the buttermilk which affected the rise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chicken was pretty good, but we found that the second fry didn't add much more value for the extra time and effort.
It's only worth it if you are obsessed with crispiness.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>biscuits</category><category>buttermilk</category><category>chicken</category><category>fried</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/buttermilk-brined-fried-chicken-and-biscuits/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 19:38:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spicy Chili Crisp Gifts</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/spicy-chili-crisp-gifts/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm visiting my family this weekend. 
I made a couple gifts for some of them and I felt like I needed to make enough for all of them.
I've also been obsessed with the &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/homemade-spicy-chili-crisp"&gt;chili crisp recipe&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GezQyVRQRzU"&gt;Sohla El-Waylly&lt;/a&gt; during her time at Serious Eats.
It's a wonderful combination of fried shallots and garlic for crunch, dried chilis for heat, and Asian spices (most notably Szechuan peppercorns) for aroma.
I've been trading it with my friends for some of their food products, such as ground deer meat and homemade &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X3DUkE6cgUg"&gt;Dongo&lt;/a&gt;.
So, I thought sharing my obsession would be the perfect gift for the rest of my family. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I didn't start the process until 8PM which was a poor decision. 
I finished cooking and cleaning around midnight.
I would highly recommend getting others to help make this recipe.
In fact, make it a party, make a big batch, and send everyone home with their own.
Deseeding the chilis takes the most time.
The Arbol chilis in particular are the most annoying due to their small size and large quantity.
Frying the shallots also takes some time and practice.
It requires constant stirring and attention because they soggy to crisp in less than a minute. 
I like to stir with chopsticks as the shallots don't attach to them very much.
The rest of the process is pretty straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been actively searching for something that this &lt;em&gt;doesn't&lt;/em&gt; work well with and so far, I've come up empty.
Here is a categorization of things I've tried the chili crisp with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Great&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By the spoonful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pizza&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eggs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avocado toast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pasta sauce (a la aglio e olio)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken salad wraps/sandwiches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cookies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caramel Girl Scout cookies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oatmeal Creampie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vanilla ice cream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Okay&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Bad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing yet!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll keep updating this list as I try new things.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chili</category><category>crisp</category><category>gift</category><category>spicy</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/spicy-chili-crisp-gifts/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 14:37:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Halal Cart-Style Chicken and Tzatziki</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/halal-cart-style-chicken-and-tzatziki/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My roommate has a favorite &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OOkL5d8t1sM"&gt;tzatziki recipe&lt;/a&gt; he likes to make.
When he told me he was going to make that and nothing else, I decided to help him round out the meal. 
I made the chicken and rice from Serious Eats' &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/serious-eats-halal-cart-style-chicken-and-rice-white-sauce-recipe"&gt;Halal Cart-Style Chicken and Rice with White Sauce&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.themediterraneandish.com/tabouli-salad/"&gt;Tabouli salad&lt;/a&gt;.
I made the rice with some homemade chicken stock as well.
May favorite part of the meal is the chicken. 
The marinade is really excellent!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chicken</category><category>condiment</category><category>mediterranean</category><category>rice</category><category>salad</category><category>tzatziki</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/halal-cart-style-chicken-and-tzatziki/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 18:17:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chicken Katsu Sandwiches</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chicken-katsu-sandwiches/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I still have a bunch of coleslaw from the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/impromptu-bbq-potluck/"&gt;Impromptu BBQ Potluck&lt;/a&gt; so my roommate suggested we make &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BOsikxHW0JQ"&gt;spicy chicken katsu sandwiches&lt;/a&gt;. 
The original recipe uses lettuce and a spicy pickle mayo, but I think the coleslaw was even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We bought extra thighs for an upcoming meal which I deboned and deskinned. 
I'll save the bones for chicken stock and the skin for schmaltz.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chicken</category><category>coleslaw</category><category>katsu</category><category>sandwich</category><category>spicy</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chicken-katsu-sandwiches/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 02:34:39 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>