<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description>A food blog.</description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 22:00:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Roasted Broccoli Soup</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/roasted-broccoli-soup/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;In my quest for colder weather foods, I decided to make &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/roasted-broccoli-soup-buttermilk-pepitas-recipe"&gt;roasted broccoli soup&lt;/a&gt;.
Broccoli soup is one of my favorite dishes since I was a kid.
This is a pretty straightforward recipe: roast/sweat vegetables, simmer in stock and buttermilk, and blend.
I wish I had roasted my broccoli longer as the flavor wasn't that pronounced, but I was getting impatient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The toasted pepitas were very good.
I really like the combination of crunchy seeds with parsley and lemon zest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think this recipe is good, but can be improved.
I think next time I will include some rosted cauliflower to round out the the flavor.
And I'll add cheese because it makes everything better.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>broccoli</category><category>buttermilk</category><category>pepitas</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soup</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/roasted-broccoli-soup/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 18:19:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Apple Sujeonggwa</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/apple-sujeonggwa/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I was searching for general fall recipes when I came across &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/apple-sujeonggwa-korean-cinnamon-ginger-punch"&gt;apple sujeonggwa&lt;/a&gt;.
Sujeonggwa is a cinnamon and ginger punch which is typically flavored with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sujeonggwa"&gt;dried persimmon&lt;/a&gt;.
The recipe I followed suggested apple chips as an easier to find substitute.
The drink was extremely good both hot and cold (the traditional way).
The best way I can describe the flavor is a spicy (from the ginger) brown sugar cinnamon pop-tart.
The pine nuts were my favorite part as they added texture and complemented the spices' flavor perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also perfect timing because my friend hosted a dumpling making party the day after I made the punch.
I brought it and some apple jack to make a simple fall cocktail.
The party was a ton of fun!
I got to practice my dumpling making skills, share some drinks and even bring some dumplings home.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>apple</category><category>cinnamon</category><category>cocktail</category><category>drinks</category><category>dumplings</category><category>ginger</category><category>korean</category><category>party</category><category>punch</category><category>Serious Eats</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/apple-sujeonggwa/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 18:18:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ground Deer Empanadas</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/ground-deer-empanadas/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I still had a pound of frozen ground deer meet from my hunter friend.
I decided to challenge myself a little and make empanadas.
I used the dough from &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/smoky-potato-and-caper-empanadas-with-cilantr-recipe"&gt;this recipe&lt;/a&gt; which incorporates some &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/masa-ball-soup-and-champurrado/"&gt;masa and chicken fat&lt;/a&gt; (other rarely used pantry ingredients).
This made the dough a little harder to work with as it was prone to tearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the filling, I winged it.
I minced a red bell pepper, sauteed that with the meat, and added some chipotle in adobo sauce to form a sloppy joe like filling.
I was able to practice forming and crimping the empanadas.
After frying, I saved the prettiest ones for my friend in the freezer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The empanadas were good on their own, but the green sauce from the above empanada recipe really completed the experience.
The acid from the limes cut through the gamey flavors.
The one thing I didn't like was how much oil the dough absorbed.
You could really tell when reheating them from frozen, because it would come bubbling out.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chipotle</category><category>deer</category><category>empanadas</category><category>masa</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>Serious Eats</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/ground-deer-empanadas/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 19:34:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roasted Eggplant With Tahini, Pine Nuts, and Lentils</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/roasted-eggplant-with-tahini-pine-nuts-and-lentils/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My roommate's girlfriend is pescetarian, so whenever we all cook together we try to make the best dishes without meat. 
I had some lentils in the pantry, so we made &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/roasted-eggplant-tahini-pine-nut-lentil-vegan-experience-recipe"&gt;roasted eggplant with tahini, pine nuts, and lentils&lt;/a&gt;. 
I made the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/vegetable-stock/"&gt;vegan stock&lt;/a&gt; early for the base of this dish.
It really elevated the lentils.
My roommate made his favorite tahini sauce, as always.
However, my favorite part was the roasted eggplant with rosemary.
The silky texture with the fresh, astringent rosemary was really perfect.
Overall, I didn't think the tahini fit well with the dish.
It was overloading the earthy flavors.
We needed to add a lot of lemon and hot sauce to balance everything again.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>eggplant</category><category>lentils</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>pine nuts</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>tahini</category><category>vegetarian</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/roasted-eggplant-with-tahini-pine-nuts-and-lentils/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 12:58:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Vegetable Stock</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/vegetable-stock/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;It's nice to have a couple killer vegan/vegetarian recipes for when you want to share a meal with &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt; friends.
This recipe for &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/hearty-vegetable-stock-vegan-recipe"&gt;Vegan Stock&lt;/a&gt; is a great base on which to build more dishes.
The secret to making a vegetable stock taste richer, is to use natural sources of glutamates (rich, meaty flavors).
Both dried mushrooms and kombu (dried kelp) are an excellent source of glutamates that are natural fits for stock.
As I'm making other dishes, I will save certain scraps in the freezer for stock.
For this stock, I saved up some mushroom, celery, and leek scraps.
Throw everything together and boil for a short while (bones in normal stock takes forever to extract).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vegan stock tastes very rich and yet still aromatic due to it only being vegetables.
The only thing that it lacks is the mouth feel you get from gelatin.
However, it's a small price to pay for sticking to your morals, especially when the flavor is so good.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>mushroom</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>stock</category><category>vegan</category><category>vegetable</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/vegetable-stock/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 21:04:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ginger Lemon Panna Cotta with Blackberries</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/ginger-lemon-panna-cotta-with-blackberries/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had panna cotta for the first time in Spain.
I enjoyed the texture the most, creamy and firm at the same time.
I randomly got a craving for it.
I found a great &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/classic-panna-cotta-vanilla-bean-recipe"&gt;blank slate recipe&lt;/a&gt; upon which to build.
However, I wanted some stronger flavors.
So, I steeped some crushed ginger and lemon peels in the warm milk for a couple hours.
The combination of sharp flavors and smooth texture was really delightful.
The acidic blackberries enhanced the effect too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I did make one mistake.
I didn't let the mixture cool long enough and the cream separated from the gelatin a bit.
It was only a visual defect though.
The dish is really delightful and simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made this recipe again steeping overnight, properly cooling before pouring, and served with blueberries.
The longer steeping created more flavor and also produced a yellow oil on the top (most likely oils from the lemon peels).
The blueberries I had were not strong enough to compete with the lemon and ginger.
I'd like to try macerated fruits next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend also brought up that she had made "ginger milk pudding" before.
Apparently, there is a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ginger_milk_curd"&gt;compound in ginger&lt;/a&gt; that can curdle milk at the right temperature.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>dessert</category><category>fruit</category><category>gelatin</category><category>ginger</category><category>lemon</category><category>milk</category><category>Serious Eats</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/ginger-lemon-panna-cotta-with-blackberries/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 20:49:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Peruvian Style Chicken Sandwiches</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/peruvian-style-chicken-sandwiches/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My roommate always wants to make fried chicken sandwiches.
This time I wanted to switch it up and make something a little different, &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/peruvian-style-grilled-chicken-sandwiches-recipe"&gt;Peruvian-Style Grilled-Chicken Sandwiches With Spicy Green Sauce&lt;/a&gt; and grilled vegetables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to a hardware store and bought the tiniest charcoal grill since my patio is also tiny.
I tried to grill the vegetables quickly over the chimney charcoal starter, but it was not going well.
I ended up switching to the grill to finish them off which went well.
The first batch of chicken breasts grilled nicely, though they didn't get grill marks or carmelize the sauce much.
By the time we got the final batch of chicken on the grill, it had been too long and wasn't hot enough to even cook the chicken at all.
We quickly pivoted to the oven to finish everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end results were very tasty despite all the stress.
I liked the green sauce in particular.
I really want to try this again on a functioning grill.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chicken</category><category>grill</category><category>mistake</category><category>Peruvian</category><category>sandwich</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>vegetables</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/peruvian-style-chicken-sandwiches/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 03:07:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Peanut Butter Braised Pork</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/peanut-butter-braised-pork/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I saw a video from the YouTube channel &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/AboutToEat"&gt;About To Eat&lt;/a&gt; for various ways to cook with peanut butter.
The braised pork interested me and I had some pork belly leftover from the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pasta-carbonara/"&gt;pasta carbonara&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/xXvA1cKfpTs" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of the video, I also just threw some things together into a braise.
The spices I used were gochugaru (Korean chili powder), Szechuan peppercorns, and Chinese five spice powder.
The sauce was &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; flavorful, almost too much.
I served it with white rice, sliced scallions, and an egg fried in the pork fat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was very good and made me happy to use some leftovers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>About To Eat</category><category>braise</category><category>gochugaru</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>peanut butter</category><category>pork belly</category><category>rice</category><category>Szechuan</category><category>Youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/peanut-butter-braised-pork/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 01:10:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cauliflower Cake</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/cauliflower-cake/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had an extra head of cauliflower from the time we made &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/fried-cauliflower-wings/"&gt;fried cauliflower "wings"&lt;/a&gt;.
I found a recipe for &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/cauliflower-cake-from-plenty-more"&gt;cauliflower cake&lt;/a&gt; that sounded interesting.
In essence you pre-cook some cauliflower, add it to a savory cake batter, and bake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to this dish is the spices.
I had some home grown rosemary to cook the onion and garlic with which was really nice.
The recipe also calls for nigella seeds which I don't have.
I followed the recommendations from &lt;a href="https://www.thespruceeats.com/what-is-nigella-sativa-1763087"&gt;The Spruce Eats&lt;/a&gt; for substitutions.
I ended up using a combination of celery seeds, oregano, caraway seeds, cumin seeds, and onion powder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This batter uses a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of eggs as well.
That combined with the cheese makes the texture somewhere between a moist cake and a quiche.
This was actually a huge hit.
I highly recommend making this cake.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cake</category><category>cauliflower</category><category>eggs</category><category>onion</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>rosemary</category><category>Serious Eats</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/cauliflower-cake/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 18:52:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pasta Carbonara</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pasta-carbonara/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had some egg yolks left over from making &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/homemade-klondike-bars/"&gt;homemade klondike bars&lt;/a&gt;, so I decided to make some pasta carbonara.
Traditionally, pasta carbonara is made with guanciale, cured pork jowl.
It is somewhat difficult to get in the United States and bacon or pork belly is often suggested as an alternative.
I used half a pound of peppered, cured pork belly diced and rendered until mostly crisp.
For the sauce, I combined the three leftover egg yolks, about 100 grams each of parmesan and pecorino romano cheese, a lot of cracked black pepper, and a drizzle of olive oil in a large bowl and mixed into a paste.
I also added a dash of milk leftover from the klondike bars to loosen the sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For cheese or oil based sauces, I like to cook my pasta in a small amount of water as shown in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yWaYdGQqxQU"&gt;this video for stovetop mac and cheese&lt;/a&gt; by J. Kenji Lopez-Alt.
This concentrates the starch in the water which helps emulsify the sauce.
Once the pasta is al dente, I drained most of the water and then tossed the pasta in the pan with the pork to emulsify the oil.
Then, I add the pasta and pork into the bowl with the sauce and vigorously toss it.
The residual heat in the pasta cooks the eggs to a custard-like consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pasta carbonara, cacio e pepe, and aglio e olio are all solid and quick pasta dishes that you should have at the ready.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>black pepper</category><category>egg yolk</category><category>Italian</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>parmesan</category><category>pasta</category><category>pecorino romano</category><category>pork belly</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pasta-carbonara/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 03:22:50 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>