<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description>A food blog.</description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 20:52:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Deviled Egg Salad</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/deviled-egg-salad/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I little while ago I saw a video about various sandwich "salads" by Adam Ragusea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wSn8Yzz_QbA" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I vaguely remembered the egg salad from that video and decided to make my own.
In particular, I remembered that his wife made a deviled egg style filling that the chopped whites get tossed in.
I hardboiled 4 eggs by simmering them in just enough water to cover for 14 minutes.
I threw together a deviled egg filling loosely inspired by &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/great-deviled-eggs-recipe"&gt;J. Kenji's deviled egg recipe&lt;/a&gt;.
My favorite part of this recipe is the addition of a high quality olive oil.
A peppery oil works very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I combined egg yolks, &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/two-minute-mayonnaise"&gt;homemade mayo&lt;/a&gt;, stone-ground mustard, capers, diced celery and its leaves, diced dill pickle, salt, pepper, cayenne, and paprika to create the base.
Then I whisked in some olive oil until it became a lighter consistency and added the chopped egg whites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I served the egg salad in a wrap with a few leaves of red oakleaf lettuce from my countertop aerogarden.
If you like deviled eggs, this is a great excuse to make a meal out of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>adam-ragusea</category><category>capers</category><category>celery</category><category>egg</category><category>homegrown</category><category>lettuce</category><category>mayo</category><category>pickle</category><category>salad</category><category>sandwiches</category><category>wraps</category><category>youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/deviled-egg-salad/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 13:43:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mapo Tofu</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/mapo-tofu/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dElALuJ9Xo8"&gt;J. Kenji's non-traditional mapo tofu video&lt;/a&gt; brought this dish to my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dElALuJ9Xo8" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He uses Japanese flavors to make something similar to the original dish.
As he was discussing the traditional ingredients and why he was replacing them, I realized that I could get somewhat close to the original dish with what I had on hand.
I still had to make some substitutions, but I wasn't trying to alter the fundamental flavors that much.
Luckily, Kenji also has a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/real-deal-mapo-dofu-tofu-chinese-sichuan-recipe"&gt;"real-deal" mapo tofu recipe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I replaced:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xiaoxing wine with a mixture of dry Sherry and sake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken stock with beef boullion (I didn't want to thaw a quart to use 1/4 cup).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black bean paste with gochujang (Korean chili and bean paste).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roasted chili oil with my &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/spicy-chili-crisp-gifts/"&gt;chili crisp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also reduced the amount of Sichuan peppercorns by half because the chili crisp already has some in it.
For that reason, I only toasted and fried the peppercorns rather than grind them and add it back to the final dish.
I felt like it was a reasonable step to take out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran into a few problems making this dish.
First, I used too much oil, so it was hard to emulsify into a sauce.
I ended up adding twice the corn starch slurry and the sauce still broke easily when it cooled down.
Even though I added no extra salt, this dish was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; salty.
The chili crisp and gochujang are fairly salty, but I think I added too much beef boullion for the 1/4 cup stock I was supposed to use.
To fix this problem, I served the mapo tofu with unsalted, buttered rice to dilute the salt.
The final issue is that there was not enough heat or numbing (the málà flavor).
I wish that I had included more Sichuan peppercorns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's still a really good dish that I want to try again.
Hopefully next time it will be strong enough to really activate some endorphins.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>beef</category><category>garlic</category><category>ginger</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>rice</category><category>seriouseats</category><category>Sichuan</category><category>spicy</category><category>tofu</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/mapo-tofu/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 13:30:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Stuffed Cabbage Rolls (Golubtsi)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/stuffed-cabbage-rolls-golubtsi/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently saw &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/helenrennie"&gt;Helen Rennie's&lt;/a&gt; video for stuffed cabbage rolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/HmtK5er6GSc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I love cabbage, I really wanted to try it.
I have a few pounds of ground deer meat that I got from a hunter friend, so I replaced the veal in the meatloaf mix with deer.
I also used the optional gelatin as a safegaurd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trimming the stems of the cabbage leaves was a great way to increase the flexibility of the leaves.
The filling was still a bit too crumbly at the end.
I could add more binders to the mix (breadcrumbs and eggs), and/or knead the mixture more to get it tighter.
My sauce also didn't reduce much during the braise, but that is not a problem when serving the rolls browned as suggested in the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of steps in the process, but it felt very manageable with two people.
One of us focused on the cabbage and sauce while the other focused on the filling and forming of the rolls.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>beef</category><category>cabbage</category><category>carrot</category><category>deer</category><category>golubtsi</category><category>helen-rennie</category><category>meatloaf</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>rice</category><category>stuffed</category><category>tomato</category><category>youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/stuffed-cabbage-rolls-golubtsi/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:50:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Korean Cheese Corn</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/korean-cheese-corn/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had a lot of leftover frozen corn, so I made &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/korean-corn-cheese-5196495"&gt;Korean Cheese Corn&lt;/a&gt;.
I didn't have doenjang, so I replaced it with white miso and a little gochujang.
It's decent, but I didn't like it as the main course. 
It would probably be much better with lots of beer and other appetizers like the article says.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>appetizer</category><category>bar</category><category>cheese</category><category>corn</category><category>gochujang</category><category>korean</category><category>meh</category><category>miso</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>seriouseats</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/korean-cheese-corn/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:44:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chicory Chocolate Banana Cake</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chicory-chocolate-banana-cake/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I bought some chicory root online to explore some new tea blends and coffee alternative.
However, I bought far too much for just some experiments.
As usual, I searched around for some recipes to use more of it.
I decided to make &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/new-orleans-snack-cake"&gt;chicory chocolate banana cake&lt;/a&gt;.
It's definitely a bit odd, but turned out very good after sitting for a couple days.
I'd describe it as a coffee banana brownie.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>banana</category><category>cake</category><category>chicory</category><category>chocolate</category><category>coffee</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>seriouseats</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chicory-chocolate-banana-cake/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:43:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spinach and Feta Galette</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/spinach-and-feta-galette/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a video by a new-to-me food youtuber, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdTLhjAGVI_XDAuXrobtI6Q"&gt;Helen Rennie&lt;/a&gt;, for a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YJn1jBlC2w8"&gt;Spinach and Feta Pie with Pizza Dough&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/YJn1jBlC2w8" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really liked the idea of making a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galette"&gt;galette&lt;/a&gt; (laziest/best way to make pie) with a no-knead pizza dough rather than a fiddly pie dough.
You mix up a pizza dough until it just comes together and then let it cold ferment 1-4 days in the fridge to develop gluten and flavor.
The process makes the dough extremely easy to shape later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real star of the show was the filling.
Helen's suggestion to use all sorts of herbs really improves on the standard spinach pie formula.
Spinach and feta alone, while it provides a nice earthiness, is too one note for me.
So, the extra accents that the herbs provided are crucial.
I added parsley, green onions, and a dash of dried tarragon.
I couldn't get fresh dill on short notice, but I would have loved to add that as well.
I also coerced my roommate into making his favorite &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OOkL5d8t1sM"&gt;tzatziki&lt;/a&gt; to contribute to the meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OOkL5d8t1sM" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did have a small issue with the technique presented in the video.
My tongs are not silicone tipped, so they ripped the parchment that had become brittle in the oven.
I wonder if a silicone mat might have worked better or if it would not have survived those temperatures directly on the oven rack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://maxb2.github.io/food/images/spinach-feta-galette.jpg" width="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>feta</category><category>galette</category><category>helen-rennie</category><category>herbs</category><category>pie</category><category>pizza</category><category>spinach</category><category>tarragon</category><category>tzatziki</category><category>youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/spinach-and-feta-galette/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 18:06:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Squash and Miso Soup From the Pantry</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/squash-and-miso-soup-from-the-pantry/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/miso-squash-soup-recipe"&gt;Miso-Squash Soup With Sesame-Ginger Apples&lt;/a&gt;, but I couldn't find all the ingredients.
In particular, I couldn't find bonito flakes at the normal place.
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Katsuobushi"&gt;Bonito flakes (katsuobushi)&lt;/a&gt; are simmered, smoked and fermented skipjack tuna.
They give dashi (kombu + katsuobushi), a japanese fish stock which is the base of miso soup, a smoky/meaty flavor.
I couldn't even find it (or instant dashi for that matter!) in the biggest Asian market in my city.
So, I had to improvise a bit.
A while ago, I was really into making different kinds of stocks.
I had frozen quarts of a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/hearty-vegetable-stock-vegan-recipe"&gt;vegan stock&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/fish-stock-fumet-recipe"&gt;French fish stock (fumet)&lt;/a&gt;.
I decided to replace the dashi with a combination of these two stocks because the vegan stock included kombu and dried mushrooms while the fumet was the only fishy stock I had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I boosted the fish flavor with some anchovy paste that I normally use in Italian dishes.
I also used two acorn squash instead of the butternut asked for in the recipe.
I like acorn squash because you can eat the thinner skin once cooked and they work very well in braised dishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like this dish because it reminds me of fall with the squash and apples, but still has a distinct flavor from the Asian ingredients.
Emptying my older pantry items is a big plus as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>acorn</category><category>apple</category><category>bonito</category><category>dashi</category><category>fish</category><category>fumet</category><category>katsuobushi</category><category>miso</category><category>pantry</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>seriouseats</category><category>soup</category><category>squash</category><category>stock</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/squash-and-miso-soup-from-the-pantry/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:05:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Carrot Cake Jam and Cheesecake</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/carrot-cake-jam-and-cheesecake/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I visited my family recently for Easter.
We cook a big meal with a ham and multiple soup options.
My sister and I requested extra vegetables for crudités.
We ended up getting too much and I brought home &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of carrots.
I was searching for a carrot cake recipe and stumbled across a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/carrot-cake-conserve-recipe"&gt;carrot cake conserve recipe&lt;/a&gt;.
I decided to make it because it was weird and I still had some commercial pectin that I was too scared to use in my &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/sous-vide-raspberry-hibiscus-cheesecake/"&gt;raspberry hibiscus jam&lt;/a&gt;.
I had reservations on using pineapple, but it turned out really well.
It doesn't taste too much of any of the fruit included and truly does taste like carrot cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I combined this jam with my favorite &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/sous-vide-raspberry-hibiscus-cheesecake/"&gt;sous vide cheesecake recipe&lt;/a&gt; to make carrot cheesecake.
Instead of using graham crackers, I just sprinkled chopped walnuts on top.
I like the cheesecake a lot, but my favorite way to eat the jam is on a bagel with cream cheese and walnuts.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cake</category><category>carrot</category><category>cheesecake</category><category>goodeats</category><category>jam</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>pectin</category><category>preserves</category><category>raisin</category><category>seriouseats</category><category>sous-vide</category><category>walnut</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/carrot-cake-jam-and-cheesecake/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 18:03:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Schmaltz, Garlic Confit, and Matzo Ball Soup</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/schmaltz-garlic-confit-and-matzo-ball-soup/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;As previously mentioned, I like to buy whole chickens, break them down my self, and use the carcasses to make homemade stock.
However, this means I also have a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of chicken skin saved up as well.
I had 3 quart bags filled with skin and decided something needed to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the only thing I can really think to do with lots of chicken skin is to render out the fat, otherwise known as schmaltz.
Making schmaltz is pretty easy, just combine the skin with some water to start the rendering process and continue to cook until the fat is all rendered out.
I chopped the skin into smaller pieces to aid the rendering and was the most time consuming part.
Optionally, you can add some diced onion near the end to add some flavor. 
I ended up getting 1.5 pints of schmaltz from all that skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I made was confit garlic.
I packed a bunch of garlic cloves in a mason jar with the schmaltz and cooked it with an immersion circulator (sous vide) at 190F until lightly golden brown (about 6 hours).
The garlic cloves turn jammy and can be used as a savory spread.
I took it to a family gathering and added it to mashed potatos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I made was &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/the-best-matzo-balls-recipe"&gt;Matzo Ball Soup&lt;/a&gt; with some homemade stock and off the shelf matzo meal.
The schmaltz is added to the matzo balls for tenderness and flavor.
It reminded me of a chicken noodle soup with dumplings instead of noodles.
I also added extra dill because it's one of my favorite herbs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>carrot</category><category>chicken</category><category>confit</category><category>dill</category><category>fat</category><category>garlic</category><category>matzo</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>schmaltz</category><category>seriouseats</category><category>soup</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/schmaltz-garlic-confit-and-matzo-ball-soup/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 02:12:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Charcuterie and Cutting Boards</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/charcuterie-and-cutting-boards/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had a work retreat this week. 
The second half of the day was a fun activity where we made our own cutting boards at a woodworking studio.
It was a lot of fun as my whole team is made of creative people. 
I also used to do a lot of woodworking when I was younger and it was nice to return to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made some standard edge grain cutting boards that you might see sold by an artist at a Farmer's market. 
The one thing that &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; surprised me was that during gluing the boards were only clamped for 30 minutes.
The leader of the class made the process really time efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward, a lady came and taught us how to make a charcuterie arangement on the boards we just made.
It was a fun time of drinking and making food art.
However, my salami rose looked more like a sombrero, so I decorated it as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://maxb2.github.io/food/images/charcuterie-board.jpg" width="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>charcuterie</category><category>retreat</category><category>woodworking</category><category>work</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/charcuterie-and-cutting-boards/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 02:09:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>