<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about Adam Ragusea)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/adam-ragusea.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 22:16:32 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fennel and Bok Choy Sheet Pan Pasta</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/fennel-and-bok-choy-sheet-pan-pasta/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I saw a video for simple &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=azNHrhGoOrc"&gt;sheet pan pasta dishes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/azNHrhGoOrc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had made something similar to the tomato based one years ago (the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U3gvRjIQ6Lo"&gt;viral baked feta pasta thing&lt;/a&gt;).
So, I decided to try the more unusual fennel, radicchio, and white bean recipe.
However, I couldn't find radicchio and the fennel I did find was pretty anemic.
He described radicchio (I've never had it) as a bitter cross between lettuce and cabbage.
Bok choy sounded like a close enough alternative since it has a hard cabbage side and a leafy lettuce side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I broiled everything like in the video.
I especially liked the light charring on the bok choy leaves.
I did find that it needed &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; cheese and lemon (he said one or the other).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought this dish was alright, but nothing to write home about.
That's a weird phrase since I am literally writing about it...
Anyway, I like the method and will try again with other combinations.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Adam Ragusea</category><category>bok choy</category><category>fennel</category><category>pasta</category><category>sheet pan</category><category>Youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/fennel-and-bok-choy-sheet-pan-pasta/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 02:36:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Practical Baked Alaska</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/practical-baked-alaska/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Baked Alaska has been a running joke with my culinary friends for a few years.
We would make the most annoying menus possible for hypothetical events.
It would include Baked Alaska, Beef Wellington, truffle anything, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I saw a video for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AEUSxRNlodc"&gt;practical Baked Alaska&lt;/a&gt; I knew I had to try it.
It also helped that my friends were having a small Independence Day gathering and that I'm looking for stand mixer projects to use my new toy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/AEUSxRNlodc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practical approach is to make each component separately and assemble in one pan.
The chocolate cake is dense, almost a brownie, and has a large fat ration to keep it from freezing rock hard.
The best approach for the ice cream is to just buy it and let it soften a little before spreading on the chilled cake.
My favorite part of this recipe is that while the egg yolks and whites are separated, they are all used.
I really hate having egg parts hanging around in the fridge that I can't find a use for.
The Italian Meringue was straight forward, but it was my first time making any meringue.
I'm just grateful that I didn't splatter the lava hot syrup on myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you just layer everything in the cake pan and freeze until serving.
Before serving, you are supposed to scorch the meringue to add a toasted marshmallow flavor.
I went to a hardware store to buy a cheap butane torch.
It turned out to be a normal cigarette lighter with a fancy nozzle.
It had issues staying lit, so I broiled the whole dish for &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; seconds and refroze it for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a really good dessert, impressive looking too, but it ruined the party by making everyone tired.
Because of the extra time it took to make each component, I'd probably only make this again for special occassions.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Adam Ragusea</category><category>cake</category><category>chocolate</category><category>dessert</category><category>ice cream</category><category>italian meringue</category><category>Youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/practical-baked-alaska/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:06:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ginger Spice Brownies and 2 Bowl Ice Cream</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/ginger-spice-brownies-and-2-bowl-ice-cream/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My roommate's girlfriend makes a lot of chocolate desserts that he brings home to share with me.
She made some really good brownies which inspired me to return the favor.
However, I wanted to make it a little weirder, so I used Serious Eats' &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/ginger-spice-brownies-5216863"&gt;ginger spice brownies recipe&lt;/a&gt;.
This is a heavily spiced dessert akin to gingerbread.
The brownies are great with a complex flavor, but they ended up being cakier than I prefer.
The recipe calls for the cake to register at 210°F, which  may be the culprit, or perhaps too much flour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it includes such intense flavors, I thought it would be nice to pair it with something fatty to balance it.
I took the opportunity to try Adam Ragusea's &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p-SikBqk2PM"&gt;2 Bowl Ice Cream&lt;/a&gt; method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/p-SikBqk2PM" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a few problems with this method.
While I did incorporate a significant amount of air, I never got to stiff peaks while whipping the ice cream base.
I think that may be because I added too much milk, throwing off the fat to water ratio.
The base didn't deflate much on the second mixing either.
I also accidentally added peppermint extract instead of vanilla, so I had to pivot to a mint chocolate chip ice cream.
Luckily, the ginger spice brownies still go well with mint.
I ended up with 2 and a half quarts which was way more than I expected (probably due to the retained air).&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Adam Ragusea</category><category>baking</category><category>brownies</category><category>ginger</category><category>ice cream</category><category>mint</category><category>mistake</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>spice</category><category>Youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/ginger-spice-brownies-and-2-bowl-ice-cream/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 01:17:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Deviled Egg Salad</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/deviled-egg-salad/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I little while ago I saw a video about various sandwich "salads" by Adam Ragusea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wSn8Yzz_QbA" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I vaguely remembered the egg salad from that video and decided to make my own.
In particular, I remembered that his wife made a deviled egg style filling that the chopped whites get tossed in.
I hardboiled 4 eggs by simmering them in just enough water to cover for 14 minutes.
I threw together a deviled egg filling loosely inspired by &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/great-deviled-eggs-recipe"&gt;J. Kenji's deviled egg recipe&lt;/a&gt;.
My favorite part of this recipe is the addition of a high quality olive oil.
A peppery oil works very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I combined egg yolks, &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/two-minute-mayonnaise"&gt;homemade mayo&lt;/a&gt;, stone-ground mustard, capers, diced celery and its leaves, diced dill pickle, salt, pepper, cayenne, and paprika to create the base.
Then I whisked in some olive oil until it became a lighter consistency and added the chopped egg whites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I served the egg salad in a wrap with a few leaves of red oakleaf lettuce from my countertop aerogarden.
If you like deviled eggs, this is a great excuse to make a meal out of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Adam Ragusea</category><category>capers</category><category>celery</category><category>egg</category><category>homegrown</category><category>lettuce</category><category>mayo</category><category>pickle</category><category>salad</category><category>sandwiches</category><category>wraps</category><category>Youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/deviled-egg-salad/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 13:43:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>