<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about beef)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/beef.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 20:52:48 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Mapo Tofu</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/mapo-tofu/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dElALuJ9Xo8"&gt;J. Kenji's non-traditional mapo tofu video&lt;/a&gt; brought this dish to my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dElALuJ9Xo8" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He uses Japanese flavors to make something similar to the original dish.
As he was discussing the traditional ingredients and why he was replacing them, I realized that I could get somewhat close to the original dish with what I had on hand.
I still had to make some substitutions, but I wasn't trying to alter the fundamental flavors that much.
Luckily, Kenji also has a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/real-deal-mapo-dofu-tofu-chinese-sichuan-recipe"&gt;"real-deal" mapo tofu recipe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I replaced:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xiaoxing wine with a mixture of dry Sherry and sake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken stock with beef boullion (I didn't want to thaw a quart to use 1/4 cup).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black bean paste with gochujang (Korean chili and bean paste).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roasted chili oil with my &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/spicy-chili-crisp-gifts/"&gt;chili crisp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also reduced the amount of Sichuan peppercorns by half because the chili crisp already has some in it.
For that reason, I only toasted and fried the peppercorns rather than grind them and add it back to the final dish.
I felt like it was a reasonable step to take out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran into a few problems making this dish.
First, I used too much oil, so it was hard to emulsify into a sauce.
I ended up adding twice the corn starch slurry and the sauce still broke easily when it cooled down.
Even though I added no extra salt, this dish was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; salty.
The chili crisp and gochujang are fairly salty, but I think I added too much beef boullion for the 1/4 cup stock I was supposed to use.
To fix this problem, I served the mapo tofu with unsalted, buttered rice to dilute the salt.
The final issue is that there was not enough heat or numbing (the málà flavor).
I wish that I had included more Sichuan peppercorns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's still a really good dish that I want to try again.
Hopefully next time it will be strong enough to really activate some endorphins.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>beef</category><category>garlic</category><category>ginger</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>rice</category><category>seriouseats</category><category>Sichuan</category><category>spicy</category><category>tofu</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/mapo-tofu/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 13:30:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Stuffed Cabbage Rolls (Golubtsi)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/stuffed-cabbage-rolls-golubtsi/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently saw &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/helenrennie"&gt;Helen Rennie's&lt;/a&gt; video for stuffed cabbage rolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/HmtK5er6GSc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I love cabbage, I really wanted to try it.
I have a few pounds of ground deer meat that I got from a hunter friend, so I replaced the veal in the meatloaf mix with deer.
I also used the optional gelatin as a safegaurd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trimming the stems of the cabbage leaves was a great way to increase the flexibility of the leaves.
The filling was still a bit too crumbly at the end.
I could add more binders to the mix (breadcrumbs and eggs), and/or knead the mixture more to get it tighter.
My sauce also didn't reduce much during the braise, but that is not a problem when serving the rolls browned as suggested in the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of steps in the process, but it felt very manageable with two people.
One of us focused on the cabbage and sauce while the other focused on the filling and forming of the rolls.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>beef</category><category>cabbage</category><category>carrot</category><category>deer</category><category>golubtsi</category><category>helen-rennie</category><category>meatloaf</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>rice</category><category>stuffed</category><category>tomato</category><category>youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/stuffed-cabbage-rolls-golubtsi/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:50:18 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>