<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about cake)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/cake.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 20:56:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Pumpkin Skillet Coffee Cake</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pumpkin-skillet-coffee-cake/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;On occasion I will scour the internet for recipes to use up an indegredient I have too much of (see the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/pantry-raid/"&gt;pantry-raid&lt;/a&gt; tag).
This time I was looking for old-fashioned oatmeal recipes, but it led me to another unused ingredient, pureed pumpkin.
I originally bought it when I was experimenting with a low-carb diet and didn't really like it in less sweet applications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serendipitously, a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/pumpkin-skillet-coffeecake-with-streusel-topping"&gt;pumpkin skillet coffee cake with oatmeal streusel&lt;/a&gt; could use both of these ingredients.
I really liked this cake, especially the texture that the white chocolate adds.
I didn't have any pecans, so I replaced them with some walnuts and pepitas (green pumpkin seeds).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this only used a fraction of each ingredient.
It didn't even use the whole can of pureed pumpkin that I opened.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cake</category><category>coffee</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>pumpkin</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>skillet</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pumpkin-skillet-coffee-cake/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 14:51:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Practical Baked Alaska</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/practical-baked-alaska/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Baked Alaska has been a running joke with my culinary friends for a few years.
We would make the most annoying menus possible for hypothetical events.
It would include Baked Alaska, Beef Wellington, truffle anything, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I saw a video for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AEUSxRNlodc"&gt;practical Baked Alaska&lt;/a&gt; I knew I had to try it.
It also helped that my friends were having a small Independence Day gathering and that I'm looking for stand mixer projects to use my new toy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/AEUSxRNlodc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practical approach is to make each component separately and assemble in one pan.
The chocolate cake is dense, almost a brownie, and has a large fat ration to keep it from freezing rock hard.
The best approach for the ice cream is to just buy it and let it soften a little before spreading on the chilled cake.
My favorite part of this recipe is that while the egg yolks and whites are separated, they are all used.
I really hate having egg parts hanging around in the fridge that I can't find a use for.
The Italian Meringue was straight forward, but it was my first time making any meringue.
I'm just grateful that I didn't splatter the lava hot syrup on myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you just layer everything in the cake pan and freeze until serving.
Before serving, you are supposed to scorch the meringue to add a toasted marshmallow flavor.
I went to a hardware store to buy a cheap butane torch.
It turned out to be a normal cigarette lighter with a fancy nozzle.
It had issues staying lit, so I broiled the whole dish for &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; seconds and refroze it for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a really good dessert, impressive looking too, but it ruined the party by making everyone tired.
Because of the extra time it took to make each component, I'd probably only make this again for special occassions.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Adam Ragusea</category><category>cake</category><category>chocolate</category><category>dessert</category><category>ice cream</category><category>italian meringue</category><category>youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/practical-baked-alaska/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:06:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chicory Chocolate Banana Cake</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chicory-chocolate-banana-cake/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I bought some chicory root online to explore some new tea blends and coffee alternative.
However, I bought far too much for just some experiments.
As usual, I searched around for some recipes to use more of it.
I decided to make &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/new-orleans-snack-cake"&gt;chicory chocolate banana cake&lt;/a&gt;.
It's definitely a bit odd, but turned out very good after sitting for a couple days.
I'd describe it as a coffee banana brownie.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>banana</category><category>cake</category><category>chicory</category><category>chocolate</category><category>coffee</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>Serious Eats</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chicory-chocolate-banana-cake/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:43:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Carrot Cake Jam and Cheesecake</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/carrot-cake-jam-and-cheesecake/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I visited my family recently for Easter.
We cook a big meal with a ham and multiple soup options.
My sister and I requested extra vegetables for crudités.
We ended up getting too much and I brought home &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of carrots.
I was searching for a carrot cake recipe and stumbled across a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/carrot-cake-conserve-recipe"&gt;carrot cake conserve recipe&lt;/a&gt;.
I decided to make it because it was weird and I still had some commercial pectin that I was too scared to use in my &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/sous-vide-raspberry-hibiscus-cheesecake/"&gt;raspberry hibiscus jam&lt;/a&gt;.
I had reservations on using pineapple, but it turned out really well.
It doesn't taste too much of any of the fruit included and truly does taste like carrot cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I combined this jam with my favorite &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/sous-vide-raspberry-hibiscus-cheesecake/"&gt;sous vide cheesecake recipe&lt;/a&gt; to make carrot cheesecake.
Instead of using graham crackers, I just sprinkled chopped walnuts on top.
I like the cheesecake a lot, but my favorite way to eat the jam is on a bagel with cream cheese and walnuts.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cake</category><category>carrot</category><category>cheesecake</category><category>goodeats</category><category>jam</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>pectin</category><category>preserves</category><category>raisin</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>sous-vide</category><category>walnut</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/carrot-cake-jam-and-cheesecake/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 18:03:54 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>