<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about carrot)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/carrot.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 12:47:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Stuffed Cabbage Rolls (Golubtsi)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/stuffed-cabbage-rolls-golubtsi/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently saw &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/helenrennie"&gt;Helen Rennie's&lt;/a&gt; video for stuffed cabbage rolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/HmtK5er6GSc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I love cabbage, I really wanted to try it.
I have a few pounds of ground deer meat that I got from a hunter friend, so I replaced the veal in the meatloaf mix with deer.
I also used the optional gelatin as a safegaurd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trimming the stems of the cabbage leaves was a great way to increase the flexibility of the leaves.
The filling was still a bit too crumbly at the end.
I could add more binders to the mix (breadcrumbs and eggs), and/or knead the mixture more to get it tighter.
My sauce also didn't reduce much during the braise, but that is not a problem when serving the rolls browned as suggested in the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of steps in the process, but it felt very manageable with two people.
One of us focused on the cabbage and sauce while the other focused on the filling and forming of the rolls.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>beef</category><category>cabbage</category><category>carrot</category><category>deer</category><category>golubtsi</category><category>Helen Rennie</category><category>meatloaf</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>rice</category><category>stuffed</category><category>tomato</category><category>youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/stuffed-cabbage-rolls-golubtsi/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:50:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Carrot Cake Jam and Cheesecake</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/carrot-cake-jam-and-cheesecake/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I visited my family recently for Easter.
We cook a big meal with a ham and multiple soup options.
My sister and I requested extra vegetables for crudités.
We ended up getting too much and I brought home &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of carrots.
I was searching for a carrot cake recipe and stumbled across a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/carrot-cake-conserve-recipe"&gt;carrot cake conserve recipe&lt;/a&gt;.
I decided to make it because it was weird and I still had some commercial pectin that I was too scared to use in my &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/sous-vide-raspberry-hibiscus-cheesecake/"&gt;raspberry hibiscus jam&lt;/a&gt;.
I had reservations on using pineapple, but it turned out really well.
It doesn't taste too much of any of the fruit included and truly does taste like carrot cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I combined this jam with my favorite &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/sous-vide-raspberry-hibiscus-cheesecake/"&gt;sous vide cheesecake recipe&lt;/a&gt; to make carrot cheesecake.
Instead of using graham crackers, I just sprinkled chopped walnuts on top.
I like the cheesecake a lot, but my favorite way to eat the jam is on a bagel with cream cheese and walnuts.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cake</category><category>carrot</category><category>cheesecake</category><category>goodeats</category><category>jam</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>pectin</category><category>preserves</category><category>raisin</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>sous-vide</category><category>walnut</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/carrot-cake-jam-and-cheesecake/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 18:03:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Schmaltz, Garlic Confit, and Matzo Ball Soup</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/schmaltz-garlic-confit-and-matzo-ball-soup/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;As previously mentioned, I like to buy whole chickens, break them down my self, and use the carcasses to make homemade stock.
However, this means I also have a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of chicken skin saved up as well.
I had 3 quart bags filled with skin and decided something needed to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the only thing I can really think to do with lots of chicken skin is to render out the fat, otherwise known as schmaltz.
Making schmaltz is pretty easy, just combine the skin with some water to start the rendering process and continue to cook until the fat is all rendered out.
I chopped the skin into smaller pieces to aid the rendering and was the most time consuming part.
Optionally, you can add some diced onion near the end to add some flavor. 
I ended up getting 1.5 pints of schmaltz from all that skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I made was confit garlic.
I packed a bunch of garlic cloves in a mason jar with the schmaltz and cooked it with an immersion circulator (sous vide) at 190F until lightly golden brown (about 6 hours).
The garlic cloves turn jammy and can be used as a savory spread.
I took it to a family gathering and added it to mashed potatos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I made was &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/the-best-matzo-balls-recipe"&gt;Matzo Ball Soup&lt;/a&gt; with some homemade stock and off the shelf matzo meal.
The schmaltz is added to the matzo balls for tenderness and flavor.
It reminded me of a chicken noodle soup with dumplings instead of noodles.
I also added extra dill because it's one of my favorite herbs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>carrot</category><category>chicken</category><category>confit</category><category>dill</category><category>fat</category><category>garlic</category><category>matzo</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>schmaltz</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soup</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/schmaltz-garlic-confit-and-matzo-ball-soup/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 02:12:48 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>