<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about chili)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/chili.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 22:12:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Chili Crisp Factory</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chili-crisp-factory/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I got a bunch of friends together to make chili crisp with me because they all love it and I'm tired of doing it all in my own.
It presented a couple challenges though.
First, I decided to make a double recipe and split it three ways.
There are lot's of respiratory irritants (chili powder and sliced shallots) in this recipe so there was constant coughing, sneezing, and crying (In retrospect, not the best idea to do with friends).
We were also cooking at my friend's house rather than my kitchen.
This was only a minor challenge in that I was in charge but unfamiliar with the equipment which led to some last second scrambling.
And lastly, we started at 8PM which was a big mistake. We didn't finish until 11:30PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was still a lot of fun and we all got something to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chili</category><category>crisp</category><category>factory</category><category>friends</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>Sichuan</category><category>spicy</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chili-crisp-factory/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:45:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spicy Chili Crisp Gifts</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/spicy-chili-crisp-gifts/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm visiting my family this weekend. 
I made a couple gifts for some of them and I felt like I needed to make enough for all of them.
I've also been obsessed with the &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/homemade-spicy-chili-crisp"&gt;chili crisp recipe&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GezQyVRQRzU"&gt;Sohla El-Waylly&lt;/a&gt; during her time at Serious Eats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/GezQyVRQRzU" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's a wonderful combination of fried shallots and garlic for crunch, dried chilis for heat, and Asian spices (most notably Szechuan peppercorns) for aroma.
I've been trading it with my friends for some of their food products, such as ground deer meat and homemade &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X3DUkE6cgUg"&gt;Dongo&lt;/a&gt;.
So, I thought sharing my obsession would be the perfect gift for the rest of my family. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I didn't start the process until 8PM which was a poor decision. 
I finished cooking and cleaning around midnight.
I would highly recommend getting others to help make this recipe.
In fact, make it a party, make a big batch, and send everyone home with their own.
Deseeding the chilis takes the most time.
The Arbol chilis in particular are the most annoying due to their small size and large quantity.
Frying the shallots also takes some time and practice.
It requires constant stirring and attention because they soggy to crisp in less than a minute. 
I like to stir with chopsticks as the shallots don't attach to them very much.
The rest of the process is pretty straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been actively searching for something that this &lt;em&gt;doesn't&lt;/em&gt; work well with and so far, I've come up empty.
Here is a categorization of things I've tried the chili crisp with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Great&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By the spoonful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pizza&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eggs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avocado toast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pasta sauce (a la aglio e olio)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken salad wraps/sandwiches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cookies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caramel Girl Scout cookies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oatmeal Creampie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vanilla ice cream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Okay&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Bad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing yet!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll keep updating this list as I try new things.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chili</category><category>crisp</category><category>gift</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>Sichuan</category><category>spicy</category><category>Youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/spicy-chili-crisp-gifts/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 14:37:39 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>