<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about chocolate)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/chocolate.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 22:00:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Homemade Klondike Bars</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/homemade-klondike-bars/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had 6 egg whites left over from the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/thai-tea-cake-and-coconut-custard/"&gt;coconut custard&lt;/a&gt; I made recently.
My roommate and his girlfriend have also been eating Klondike bars a lot, so I decided to make a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/homemade-klondike-ice-cream-bars-recipe"&gt;homemade version&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kfb7bo0QCxs" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The "ice cream" is actually a combination of Swiss meringue (cooked, whipped egg whites with sugar) and whipped cream.
The texture is pretty much the same as the commercial bars.
The best part is that you can use quality chocolate which the original is severely lacking.
This recipe has a lot of leftover chocolate mixture, so I put some almonds in an icetray, covered them and froze it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recipe is pretty easy if you have a stand mixer.
It may be bearable with a hand mixer too.
The main drawback is that you must freeze things repeatedly to avoid melting while you are coating with chocolate.
It's a nice way to use up some leftover egg whites.
Ironically, we scrambled the egg whites on accident while cooking the meringue, so now I have yolks leftover.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chocolate</category><category>friends</category><category>ice cream</category><category>meringue</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>stand mixer</category><category>Stella Parks</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/homemade-klondike-bars/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 02:36:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Practical Baked Alaska</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/practical-baked-alaska/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Baked Alaska has been a running joke with my culinary friends for a few years.
We would make the most annoying menus possible for hypothetical events.
It would include Baked Alaska, Beef Wellington, truffle anything, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I saw a video for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AEUSxRNlodc"&gt;practical Baked Alaska&lt;/a&gt; I knew I had to try it.
It also helped that my friends were having a small Independence Day gathering and that I'm looking for stand mixer projects to use my new toy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/AEUSxRNlodc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practical approach is to make each component separately and assemble in one pan.
The chocolate cake is dense, almost a brownie, and has a large fat ration to keep it from freezing rock hard.
The best approach for the ice cream is to just buy it and let it soften a little before spreading on the chilled cake.
My favorite part of this recipe is that while the egg yolks and whites are separated, they are all used.
I really hate having egg parts hanging around in the fridge that I can't find a use for.
The Italian Meringue was straight forward, but it was my first time making any meringue.
I'm just grateful that I didn't splatter the lava hot syrup on myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you just layer everything in the cake pan and freeze until serving.
Before serving, you are supposed to scorch the meringue to add a toasted marshmallow flavor.
I went to a hardware store to buy a cheap butane torch.
It turned out to be a normal cigarette lighter with a fancy nozzle.
It had issues staying lit, so I broiled the whole dish for &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; seconds and refroze it for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a really good dessert, impressive looking too, but it ruined the party by making everyone tired.
Because of the extra time it took to make each component, I'd probably only make this again for special occassions.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Adam Ragusea</category><category>cake</category><category>chocolate</category><category>dessert</category><category>ice cream</category><category>italian meringue</category><category>Youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/practical-baked-alaska/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:06:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Masa Ball Soup and Champurrado</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/masa-ball-soup-and-champurrado/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;When I was researching the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/schmaltz-garlic-confit-and-matzo-ball-soup/"&gt;matzo ball soup&lt;/a&gt;, I came across something amusing: &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/how-to-make-masa-ball-soup-mexican-jewish-matzo-corn"&gt;Masa ball soup&lt;/a&gt;.
It's a Mexican take on the original dish. 
Both are essentially dumplings in chicken soup.
The dumplings here are made of masa, a specially treated corn flour used in tortillas, tamales, etc.
The last minor differences are using squash and cilantro instead of carrots and dill.
It's those changes that give the dish a Mexican flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The masa ball dough was pretty loose which made me fear that the balls would disintegrate while cooking.
Fortunately, they stayed together despite being a bit deformed.
Overall, this was the best tasting pun I've eaten, but I prefer the original a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I had the masa flour out, I decided to try making &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/champurrado-mexican-hot-chocolate-corn-drink-recipe"&gt;champurrado&lt;/a&gt;, a thickened hot chocolate drink.
I felt like the recipe was a bit lacking, so I added some cayenne, cumin, and coriander.
It was pretty good, but not the right time of year for hot chocolate.
One plus is that it sets up as a pudding when cooled which fit the season better.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>champurrado</category><category>chocolate</category><category>masa</category><category>matzo</category><category>pudding</category><category>pun</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soup</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/masa-ball-soup-and-champurrado/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 22:32:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chicory Chocolate Banana Cake</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chicory-chocolate-banana-cake/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I bought some chicory root online to explore some new tea blends and coffee alternative.
However, I bought far too much for just some experiments.
As usual, I searched around for some recipes to use more of it.
I decided to make &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/new-orleans-snack-cake"&gt;chicory chocolate banana cake&lt;/a&gt;.
It's definitely a bit odd, but turned out very good after sitting for a couple days.
I'd describe it as a coffee banana brownie.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>banana</category><category>cake</category><category>chicory</category><category>chocolate</category><category>coffee</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>Serious Eats</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chicory-chocolate-banana-cake/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:43:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>