<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about friends)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/friends.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 19:00:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fried Cauliflower "Wings"</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/fried-cauliflower-wings/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My roommate's girlfriend is pescatarian, so we try to find interesting dishes that accommodate her diet.
There is a great recipe for &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/the-vegan-experience-korean-fried-cauliflower"&gt;fried cauliflower "wings"&lt;/a&gt;.
It is good enough to rival real chicken wings.
The batter is extra crispy and the cauliflower perfectly tender.
There are recipes for a Buffalo sauce and a Korean sweet and spicy sauce.
I prefer the Korean sauce, but both are really good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also made some &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/ranch-dressing-homemade-recipe"&gt;ranch dressing&lt;/a&gt; which itself is based on a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/two-minute-mayonnaise"&gt;homemade mayo&lt;/a&gt;.
That mayo is a staple in my house.
The ranch dressing is really amazing.
It's much better with fresh herbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also made &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/toaster-oven-salmon/"&gt;toaster oven salmon&lt;/a&gt; to round out the meal.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Asian</category><category>cauliflower</category><category>deep fried</category><category>friends</category><category>ginger</category><category>Kenji</category><category>mayo</category><category>ranch</category><category>sauce</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soy</category><category>vegan</category><category>wings</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/fried-cauliflower-wings/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 02:37:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Toaster Oven Salmon</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/toaster-oven-salmon/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;While making &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/fried-cauliflower-wings/"&gt;fried cauliflower "wings"&lt;/a&gt;, we made &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/miso-glazed-salmon-in-the-toaster-oven-recipe"&gt;toaster oven salmon&lt;/a&gt;.
For the marinade I just threw together some miso, soy sauce, brown sugar, and rice vinegar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think my toaster oven is a bit underpowered, as it took much longer than the recipe suggested.
In principle though, I really enjoy the salmon covered in a marinade or flavored mayo and broiled.
The oil coating in both cases insulates the fish from the heat so as not to dry out.
Plus, the coating can get a nice browning.
I also make &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/baked-broiled-salmon-harissa-mayonnaise"&gt;broiled salmon with harissa spice mayo&lt;/a&gt; quite often.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>friends</category><category>Kenji</category><category>miso</category><category>rice vinegar</category><category>salmon</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soy</category><category>toaster oven</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/toaster-oven-salmon/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 02:36:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Homemade Klondike Bars</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/homemade-klondike-bars/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had 6 egg whites left over from the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/thai-tea-cake-and-coconut-custard/"&gt;coconut custard&lt;/a&gt; I made recently.
My roommate and his girlfriend have also been eating Klondike bars a lot, so I decided to make a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/homemade-klondike-ice-cream-bars-recipe"&gt;homemade version&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kfb7bo0QCxs" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The "ice cream" is actually a combination of Swiss meringue (cooked, whipped egg whites with sugar) and whipped cream.
The texture is pretty much the same as the commercial bars.
The best part is that you can use quality chocolate which the original is severely lacking.
This recipe has a lot of leftover chocolate mixture, so I put some almonds in an icetray, covered them and froze it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recipe is pretty easy if you have a stand mixer.
It may be bearable with a hand mixer too.
The main drawback is that you must freeze things repeatedly to avoid melting while you are coating with chocolate.
It's a nice way to use up some leftover egg whites.
Ironically, we scrambled the egg whites on accident while cooking the meringue, so now I have yolks leftover.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chocolate</category><category>friends</category><category>ice cream</category><category>meringue</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>stand mixer</category><category>Stella Parks</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/homemade-klondike-bars/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 02:36:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chili Crisp Factory</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chili-crisp-factory/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I got a bunch of friends together to make chili crisp with me because they all love it and I'm tired of doing it all in my own.
It presented a couple challenges though.
First, I decided to make a double recipe and split it three ways.
There are lot's of respiratory irritants (chili powder and sliced shallots) in this recipe so there was constant coughing, sneezing, and crying (In retrospect, not the best idea to do with friends).
We were also cooking at my friend's house rather than my kitchen.
This was only a minor challenge in that I was in charge but unfamiliar with the equipment which led to some last second scrambling.
And lastly, we started at 8PM which was a big mistake. We didn't finish until 11:30PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was still a lot of fun and we all got something to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chili</category><category>crisp</category><category>factory</category><category>friends</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>Sichuan</category><category>spicy</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/chili-crisp-factory/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:45:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Impromptu BBQ Potluck</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/impromptu-bbq-potluck/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My friend with a smoker decided to randomly make some pulled pork this weekend. 
We decided to have an impromptu potluck.
I signed up to make the side dishes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend and I had previously lamented the over-doneness of mac and cheese at typical BBQ restaurants.
So, I made some &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/classic-bechamel-baked-mac-cheese-recipe"&gt;classic baked mac and cheese&lt;/a&gt;. 
It is just parcooked pasta in a mornay sauce with breadcrumbs on top that is baked like a casserole. 
I used cellentani instead of elbow macaroni because I like the shape better.
I also added a pinch of truffle powder to the sauce for extra flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I typically don't like creamy American coleslaw because of its cloying sweetness.
However, I really wanted to top the pulled pork sandwiches with something. 
I made &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/the-food-lab-how-to-make-the-best-creamy-cole-slaw"&gt;creamy coleslaw&lt;/a&gt; by J. Kenji Lopez-Alt.
Even though it makes a giant mess, I really like this recipe.
I think the keys to success are "curing" the vegetables, and using the best quality mayonnaise.
The best quality mayo will always be homemade.
J. Kenji also has a great (fast) &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/two-minute-mayonnaise"&gt;mayo recipe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I wanted an alternative to the coleslaw, so I made &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/quick-dill-pickle-chips-recipe"&gt;quick pickles&lt;/a&gt;. 
They taste strongly of dill, garlic, and vinegar which is my favorite kind of pickle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was a great success!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Americana</category><category>barbeque</category><category>BBQ</category><category>friends</category><category>potluck</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>side-dish</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/impromptu-bbq-potluck/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 18:58:05 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>