<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about garlic)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/garlic.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 01:53:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Mapo Tofu</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/mapo-tofu/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dElALuJ9Xo8"&gt;J. Kenji's non-traditional mapo tofu video&lt;/a&gt; brought this dish to my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dElALuJ9Xo8" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He uses Japanese flavors to make something similar to the original dish.
As he was discussing the traditional ingredients and why he was replacing them, I realized that I could get somewhat close to the original dish with what I had on hand.
I still had to make some substitutions, but I wasn't trying to alter the fundamental flavors that much.
Luckily, Kenji also has a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/real-deal-mapo-dofu-tofu-chinese-sichuan-recipe"&gt;"real-deal" mapo tofu recipe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I replaced:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xiaoxing wine with a mixture of dry Sherry and sake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken stock with beef boullion (I didn't want to thaw a quart to use 1/4 cup).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black bean paste with gochujang (Korean chili and bean paste).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roasted chili oil with my &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/spicy-chili-crisp-gifts/"&gt;chili crisp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also reduced the amount of Sichuan peppercorns by half because the chili crisp already has some in it.
For that reason, I only toasted and fried the peppercorns rather than grind them and add it back to the final dish.
I felt like it was a reasonable step to take out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran into a few problems making this dish.
First, I used too much oil, so it was hard to emulsify into a sauce.
I ended up adding twice the corn starch slurry and the sauce still broke easily when it cooled down.
Even though I added no extra salt, this dish was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; salty.
The chili crisp and gochujang are fairly salty, but I think I added too much beef boullion for the 1/4 cup stock I was supposed to use.
To fix this problem, I served the mapo tofu with unsalted, buttered rice to dilute the salt.
The final issue is that there was not enough heat or numbing (the málà flavor).
I wish that I had included more Sichuan peppercorns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's still a really good dish that I want to try again.
Hopefully next time it will be strong enough to really activate some endorphins.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>beef</category><category>garlic</category><category>ginger</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>rice</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>Sichuan</category><category>spicy</category><category>tofu</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/mapo-tofu/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 13:30:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Schmaltz, Garlic Confit, and Matzo Ball Soup</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/schmaltz-garlic-confit-and-matzo-ball-soup/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;As previously mentioned, I like to buy whole chickens, break them down my self, and use the carcasses to make homemade stock.
However, this means I also have a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of chicken skin saved up as well.
I had 3 quart bags filled with skin and decided something needed to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the only thing I can really think to do with lots of chicken skin is to render out the fat, otherwise known as schmaltz.
Making schmaltz is pretty easy, just combine the skin with some water to start the rendering process and continue to cook until the fat is all rendered out.
I chopped the skin into smaller pieces to aid the rendering and was the most time consuming part.
Optionally, you can add some diced onion near the end to add some flavor. 
I ended up getting 1.5 pints of schmaltz from all that skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I made was confit garlic.
I packed a bunch of garlic cloves in a mason jar with the schmaltz and cooked it with an immersion circulator (sous vide) at 190F until lightly golden brown (about 6 hours).
The garlic cloves turn jammy and can be used as a savory spread.
I took it to a family gathering and added it to mashed potatos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I made was &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/the-best-matzo-balls-recipe"&gt;Matzo Ball Soup&lt;/a&gt; with some homemade stock and off the shelf matzo meal.
The schmaltz is added to the matzo balls for tenderness and flavor.
It reminded me of a chicken noodle soup with dumplings instead of noodles.
I also added extra dill because it's one of my favorite herbs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>carrot</category><category>chicken</category><category>confit</category><category>dill</category><category>fat</category><category>garlic</category><category>matzo</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>schmaltz</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soup</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/schmaltz-garlic-confit-and-matzo-ball-soup/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 02:12:48 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>