<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about mistake)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/mistake.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 02:32:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Ginger Spice Brownies and 2 Bowl Ice Cream</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/ginger-spice-brownies-and-2-bowl-ice-cream/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My roommate's girlfriend makes a lot of chocolate desserts that he brings home to share with me.
She made some really good brownies which inspired me to return the favor.
However, I wanted to make it a little weirder, so I used Serious Eats' &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/ginger-spice-brownies-5216863"&gt;ginger spice brownies recipe&lt;/a&gt;.
This is a heavily spiced dessert akin to gingerbread.
The brownies are great with a complex flavor, but they ended up being cakier than I prefer.
The recipe calls for the cake to register at 210°F, which  may be the culprit, or perhaps too much flour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it includes such intense flavors, I thought it would be nice to pair it with something fatty to balance it.
I took the opportunity to try Adam Ragusea's &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p-SikBqk2PM"&gt;2 Bowl Ice Cream&lt;/a&gt; method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/p-SikBqk2PM" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a few problems with this method.
While I did incorporate a significant amount of air, I never got to stiff peaks while whipping the ice cream base.
I think that may be because I added too much milk, throwing off the fat to water ratio.
The base didn't deflate much on the second mixing either.
I also accidentally added peppermint extract instead of vanilla, so I had to pivot to a mint chocolate chip ice cream.
Luckily, the ginger spice brownies still go well with mint.
I ended up with 2 and a half quarts which was way more than I expected (probably due to the retained air).&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Adam Ragusea</category><category>baking</category><category>brownies</category><category>ginger</category><category>ice cream</category><category>mint</category><category>mistake</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>spice</category><category>youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/ginger-spice-brownies-and-2-bowl-ice-cream/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 01:17:45 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>