<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about pork belly)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/pork-belly.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 04:51:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Peanut Butter Braised Pork</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/peanut-butter-braised-pork/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I saw a video from the YouTube channel &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/AboutToEat"&gt;About To Eat&lt;/a&gt; for various ways to cook with peanut butter.
The braised pork interested me and I had some pork belly leftover from the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pasta-carbonara/"&gt;pasta carbonara&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/xXvA1cKfpTs" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of the video, I also just threw some things together into a braise.
The spices I used were gochugaru (Korean chili powder), Szechuan peppercorns, and Chinese five spice powder.
The sauce was &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; flavorful, almost too much.
I served it with white rice, sliced scallions, and an egg fried in the pork fat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was very good and made me happy to use some leftovers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>About To Eat</category><category>braise</category><category>gochugaru</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>peanut butter</category><category>pork belly</category><category>rice</category><category>Szechuan</category><category>Youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/peanut-butter-braised-pork/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 01:10:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pasta Carbonara</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pasta-carbonara/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had some egg yolks left over from making &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/homemade-klondike-bars/"&gt;homemade klondike bars&lt;/a&gt;, so I decided to make some pasta carbonara.
Traditionally, pasta carbonara is made with guanciale, cured pork jowl.
It is somewhat difficult to get in the United States and bacon or pork belly is often suggested as an alternative.
I used half a pound of peppered, cured pork belly diced and rendered until mostly crisp.
For the sauce, I combined the three leftover egg yolks, about 100 grams each of parmesan and pecorino romano cheese, a lot of cracked black pepper, and a drizzle of olive oil in a large bowl and mixed into a paste.
I also added a dash of milk leftover from the klondike bars to loosen the sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For cheese or oil based sauces, I like to cook my pasta in a small amount of water as shown in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yWaYdGQqxQU"&gt;this video for stovetop mac and cheese&lt;/a&gt; by J. Kenji Lopez-Alt.
This concentrates the starch in the water which helps emulsify the sauce.
Once the pasta is al dente, I drained most of the water and then tossed the pasta in the pan with the pork to emulsify the oil.
Then, I add the pasta and pork into the bowl with the sauce and vigorously toss it.
The residual heat in the pasta cooks the eggs to a custard-like consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pasta carbonara, cacio e pepe, and aglio e olio are all solid and quick pasta dishes that you should have at the ready.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>black pepper</category><category>egg yolk</category><category>Italian</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>parmesan</category><category>pasta</category><category>pecorino romano</category><category>pork belly</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pasta-carbonara/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 03:22:50 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>