<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about rice)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/rice.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 21:40:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Peanut Butter Braised Pork</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/peanut-butter-braised-pork/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I saw a video from the YouTube channel &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/AboutToEat"&gt;About To Eat&lt;/a&gt; for various ways to cook with peanut butter.
The braised pork interested me and I had some pork belly leftover from the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pasta-carbonara/"&gt;pasta carbonara&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/xXvA1cKfpTs" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of the video, I also just threw some things together into a braise.
The spices I used were gochugaru (Korean chili powder), Szechuan peppercorns, and Chinese five spice powder.
The sauce was &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; flavorful, almost too much.
I served it with white rice, sliced scallions, and an egg fried in the pork fat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was very good and made me happy to use some leftovers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>About To Eat</category><category>braise</category><category>gochugaru</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>peanut butter</category><category>pork belly</category><category>rice</category><category>Szechuan</category><category>Youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/peanut-butter-braised-pork/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 01:10:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Shrimp Étouffée</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/shrimp-etouffee/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2017 I visited New Orleans for a work conference.
On my last day there, I had crawfish étouffée for the first time.
It was so good that it made a lasting impression on me.
Last year, I tried the crawfish étouffée from a new-ish Cajun restaurant where I live.
Unfortunately, I was not impressed.
To be fair, it was not bad, I was just comparing it to a rose-tinted memory of a dish made by the actual authorities on the dish.
Nonetheless, the experience inspired me to make étouffée myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the Serious Eats recipe for &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/shrimp-etouffee"&gt;shrimp étouffée&lt;/a&gt; since it's a bit difficult to get crawfish where I live.
It consists of two major operations: making a shrimp stock and making the étouffée itself.
The base of the stock is made from the shells of the shrimp used later in the main dish.
It is a relatively quick stock since you are only extracting flavor and not gelatin like a bone-based stock or broth.
However, it still helps to split the two operations up in time.
The recipe also makes enough stock for two batches of étouffée.
So, I froze one quart for a future use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of which brings us to the present day where I was searching for something to make and remembered the special purpose shrimp stock that had been in my freezer for a year. 
Making the étouffée itself is pretty simple, it's just make a roux, sweat some &lt;a href="https://www.thespruceeats.com/cajun-trinity-of-cooking-3052290"&gt;Cajun trinity vegetables&lt;/a&gt;, add spices and the stock, simmer until vegetables are soft, and cook your meat in the sauce.
In my opinion, the most impactful step is making the roux.
I like a "peanut butter" colored roux because it adds a complex, nutty flavor without overshadowing the other flavors.
This time, I also added some home grown garlic scapes as a garnish.
Finally, serve with rice and a dry white wine.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>butter</category><category>Cajun</category><category>cayenne</category><category>celery</category><category>Creole</category><category>etouffee</category><category>homegrown</category><category>pepper</category><category>rice</category><category>roux</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>shrimp</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/shrimp-etouffee/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 01:16:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mapo Tofu</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/mapo-tofu/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dElALuJ9Xo8"&gt;J. Kenji's non-traditional mapo tofu video&lt;/a&gt; brought this dish to my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dElALuJ9Xo8" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He uses Japanese flavors to make something similar to the original dish.
As he was discussing the traditional ingredients and why he was replacing them, I realized that I could get somewhat close to the original dish with what I had on hand.
I still had to make some substitutions, but I wasn't trying to alter the fundamental flavors that much.
Luckily, Kenji also has a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/real-deal-mapo-dofu-tofu-chinese-sichuan-recipe"&gt;"real-deal" mapo tofu recipe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I replaced:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xiaoxing wine with a mixture of dry Sherry and sake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken stock with beef boullion (I didn't want to thaw a quart to use 1/4 cup).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black bean paste with gochujang (Korean chili and bean paste).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roasted chili oil with my &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/spicy-chili-crisp-gifts/"&gt;chili crisp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also reduced the amount of Sichuan peppercorns by half because the chili crisp already has some in it.
For that reason, I only toasted and fried the peppercorns rather than grind them and add it back to the final dish.
I felt like it was a reasonable step to take out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran into a few problems making this dish.
First, I used too much oil, so it was hard to emulsify into a sauce.
I ended up adding twice the corn starch slurry and the sauce still broke easily when it cooled down.
Even though I added no extra salt, this dish was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; salty.
The chili crisp and gochujang are fairly salty, but I think I added too much beef boullion for the 1/4 cup stock I was supposed to use.
To fix this problem, I served the mapo tofu with unsalted, buttered rice to dilute the salt.
The final issue is that there was not enough heat or numbing (the málà flavor).
I wish that I had included more Sichuan peppercorns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's still a really good dish that I want to try again.
Hopefully next time it will be strong enough to really activate some endorphins.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>beef</category><category>garlic</category><category>ginger</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>rice</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>Sichuan</category><category>spicy</category><category>tofu</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/mapo-tofu/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 13:30:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Stuffed Cabbage Rolls (Golubtsi)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/stuffed-cabbage-rolls-golubtsi/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently saw &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/helenrennie"&gt;Helen Rennie's&lt;/a&gt; video for stuffed cabbage rolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/HmtK5er6GSc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I love cabbage, I really wanted to try it.
I have a few pounds of ground deer meat that I got from a hunter friend, so I replaced the veal in the meatloaf mix with deer.
I also used the optional gelatin as a safegaurd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trimming the stems of the cabbage leaves was a great way to increase the flexibility of the leaves.
The filling was still a bit too crumbly at the end.
I could add more binders to the mix (breadcrumbs and eggs), and/or knead the mixture more to get it tighter.
My sauce also didn't reduce much during the braise, but that is not a problem when serving the rolls browned as suggested in the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of steps in the process, but it felt very manageable with two people.
One of us focused on the cabbage and sauce while the other focused on the filling and forming of the rolls.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>beef</category><category>cabbage</category><category>carrot</category><category>deer</category><category>golubtsi</category><category>Helen Rennie</category><category>meatloaf</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>rice</category><category>stuffed</category><category>tomato</category><category>Youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/stuffed-cabbage-rolls-golubtsi/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:50:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Halal Cart-Style Chicken and Tzatziki</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/halal-cart-style-chicken-and-tzatziki/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My roommate has a favorite &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OOkL5d8t1sM"&gt;tzatziki recipe&lt;/a&gt; he likes to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OOkL5d8t1sM" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he told me he was going to make that and nothing else, I decided to help him round out the meal. 
I made the chicken and rice from Serious Eats' &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/serious-eats-halal-cart-style-chicken-and-rice-white-sauce-recipe"&gt;Halal Cart-Style Chicken and Rice with White Sauce&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.themediterraneandish.com/tabouli-salad/"&gt;Tabouli salad&lt;/a&gt;.
I made the rice with some homemade chicken stock as well.
May favorite part of the meal is the chicken. 
The marinade is really excellent!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chicken</category><category>condiment</category><category>Food Wishes</category><category>Mediterranean</category><category>rice</category><category>salad</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>tabouli</category><category>The Mediterranean Dish</category><category>tzatziki</category><category>Youtube</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/halal-cart-style-chicken-and-tzatziki/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 18:17:18 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>