<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about Serious Eats)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/serious-eats.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 20:36:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Apple Sujeonggwa</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/apple-sujeonggwa/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I was searching for general fall recipes when I came across &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/apple-sujeonggwa-korean-cinnamon-ginger-punch"&gt;apple sujeonggwa&lt;/a&gt;.
Sujeonggwa is a cinnamon and ginger punch which is typically flavored with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sujeonggwa"&gt;dried persimmon&lt;/a&gt;.
The recipe I followed suggested apple chips as an easier to find substitute.
The drink was extremely good both hot and cold (the traditional way).
The best way I can describe the flavor is a spicy (from the ginger) brown sugar cinnamon pop-tart.
The pine nuts were my favorite part as they added texture and complemented the spices' flavor perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also perfect timing because my friend hosted a dumpling making party the day after I made the punch.
I brought it and some apple jack to make a simple fall cocktail.
The party was a ton of fun!
I got to practice my dumpling making skills, share some drinks and even bring some dumplings home.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>apple</category><category>cinnamon</category><category>cocktail</category><category>drinks</category><category>dumplings</category><category>ginger</category><category>korean</category><category>party</category><category>punch</category><category>Serious Eats</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/apple-sujeonggwa/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 18:18:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ginger Lemon Panna Cotta with Blackberries</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/ginger-lemon-panna-cotta-with-blackberries/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had panna cotta for the first time in Spain.
I enjoyed the texture the most, creamy and firm at the same time.
I randomly got a craving for it.
I found a great &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/classic-panna-cotta-vanilla-bean-recipe"&gt;blank slate recipe&lt;/a&gt; upon which to build.
However, I wanted some stronger flavors.
So, I steeped some crushed ginger and lemon peels in the warm milk for a couple hours.
The combination of sharp flavors and smooth texture was really delightful.
The acidic blackberries enhanced the effect too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I did make one mistake.
I didn't let the mixture cool long enough and the cream separated from the gelatin a bit.
It was only a visual defect though.
The dish is really delightful and simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made this recipe again steeping overnight, properly cooling before pouring, and served with blueberries.
The longer steeping created more flavor and also produced a yellow oil on the top (most likely oils from the lemon peels).
The blueberries I had were not strong enough to compete with the lemon and ginger.
I'd like to try macerated fruits next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend also brought up that she had made "ginger milk pudding" before.
Apparently, there is a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ginger_milk_curd"&gt;compound in ginger&lt;/a&gt; that can curdle milk at the right temperature.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>dessert</category><category>fruit</category><category>gelatin</category><category>ginger</category><category>lemon</category><category>milk</category><category>Serious Eats</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/ginger-lemon-panna-cotta-with-blackberries/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 20:49:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cauliflower Cake</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/cauliflower-cake/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had an extra head of cauliflower from the time we made &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/fried-cauliflower-wings/"&gt;fried cauliflower "wings"&lt;/a&gt;.
I found a recipe for &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/cauliflower-cake-from-plenty-more"&gt;cauliflower cake&lt;/a&gt; that sounded interesting.
In essence you pre-cook some cauliflower, add it to a savory cake batter, and bake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to this dish is the spices.
I had some home grown rosemary to cook the onion and garlic with which was really nice.
The recipe also calls for nigella seeds which I don't have.
I followed the recommendations from &lt;a href="https://www.thespruceeats.com/what-is-nigella-sativa-1763087"&gt;The Spruce Eats&lt;/a&gt; for substitutions.
I ended up using a combination of celery seeds, oregano, caraway seeds, cumin seeds, and onion powder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This batter uses a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of eggs as well.
That combined with the cheese makes the texture somewhere between a moist cake and a quiche.
This was actually a huge hit.
I highly recommend making this cake.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cake</category><category>cauliflower</category><category>eggs</category><category>onion</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>rosemary</category><category>Serious Eats</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/cauliflower-cake/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 18:52:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fried Cauliflower "Wings"</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/fried-cauliflower-wings/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My roommate's girlfriend is pescatarian, so we try to find interesting dishes that accommodate her diet.
There is a great recipe for &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/the-vegan-experience-korean-fried-cauliflower"&gt;fried cauliflower "wings"&lt;/a&gt;.
It is good enough to rival real chicken wings.
The batter is extra crispy and the cauliflower perfectly tender.
There are recipes for a Buffalo sauce and a Korean sweet and spicy sauce.
I prefer the Korean sauce, but both are really good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also made some &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/ranch-dressing-homemade-recipe"&gt;ranch dressing&lt;/a&gt; which itself is based on a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/two-minute-mayonnaise"&gt;homemade mayo&lt;/a&gt;.
That mayo is a staple in my house.
The ranch dressing is really amazing.
It's much better with fresh herbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also made &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/toaster-oven-salmon/"&gt;toaster oven salmon&lt;/a&gt; to round out the meal.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Asian</category><category>cauliflower</category><category>deep fried</category><category>friends</category><category>ginger</category><category>Kenji</category><category>mayo</category><category>ranch</category><category>sauce</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soy</category><category>vegan</category><category>wings</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/fried-cauliflower-wings/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 02:37:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Toaster Oven Salmon</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/toaster-oven-salmon/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;While making &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/fried-cauliflower-wings/"&gt;fried cauliflower "wings"&lt;/a&gt;, we made &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/miso-glazed-salmon-in-the-toaster-oven-recipe"&gt;toaster oven salmon&lt;/a&gt;.
For the marinade I just threw together some miso, soy sauce, brown sugar, and rice vinegar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think my toaster oven is a bit underpowered, as it took much longer than the recipe suggested.
In principle though, I really enjoy the salmon covered in a marinade or flavored mayo and broiled.
The oil coating in both cases insulates the fish from the heat so as not to dry out.
Plus, the coating can get a nice browning.
I also make &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/baked-broiled-salmon-harissa-mayonnaise"&gt;broiled salmon with harissa spice mayo&lt;/a&gt; quite often.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>friends</category><category>Kenji</category><category>miso</category><category>rice vinegar</category><category>salmon</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soy</category><category>toaster oven</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/toaster-oven-salmon/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 02:36:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Homemade Klondike Bars</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/homemade-klondike-bars/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had 6 egg whites left over from the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/thai-tea-cake-and-coconut-custard/"&gt;coconut custard&lt;/a&gt; I made recently.
My roommate and his girlfriend have also been eating Klondike bars a lot, so I decided to make a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/homemade-klondike-ice-cream-bars-recipe"&gt;homemade version&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kfb7bo0QCxs" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The "ice cream" is actually a combination of Swiss meringue (cooked, whipped egg whites with sugar) and whipped cream.
The texture is pretty much the same as the commercial bars.
The best part is that you can use quality chocolate which the original is severely lacking.
This recipe has a lot of leftover chocolate mixture, so I put some almonds in an icetray, covered them and froze it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recipe is pretty easy if you have a stand mixer.
It may be bearable with a hand mixer too.
The main drawback is that you must freeze things repeatedly to avoid melting while you are coating with chocolate.
It's a nice way to use up some leftover egg whites.
Ironically, we scrambled the egg whites on accident while cooking the meringue, so now I have yolks leftover.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>chocolate</category><category>friends</category><category>ice cream</category><category>meringue</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>stand mixer</category><category>Stella Parks</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/homemade-klondike-bars/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 02:36:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Thai Tea Cake and Coconut Custard</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/thai-tea-cake-and-coconut-custard/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a pound of loose leaf Thai tea a while back because I really love Thai iced tea in restaurants.
For a while, I was making it all the time at home with various milks.
The drink is really good, but I wanted to find something else to try.
I found a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/thai-tea-cake-with-condensed-milk-custard-sauce-recipe"&gt;Thai tea cake with custard recipe&lt;/a&gt;.
The cake is pretty straightforward, even though I had to buy a new pan.
You just steep the tea in some warm milk before incorporating into the cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the custard, I couldn't find sweetened condensed milk, only sweetened condensed &lt;em&gt;coconut&lt;/em&gt; milk.
I felt that was perhaps a more fitting alternative anyway.
The custard was pretty standard as well.
However, it uses 6 egg yolks, so I didn't actually reduce my unused pantry ingredients with all the extra egg whites sitting around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a really great desert.
The cake becomes a nice orange color and the coconut custard awesome.
I only wish that the tea flavor were stronger.
You have to eat the cake without any custard to get any hint of tea.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cake</category><category>coconut</category><category>custard</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>tea</category><category>Thai</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/thai-tea-cake-and-coconut-custard/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 02:35:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pumpkin Sweet Swirl Buns</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pumpkin-sweet-swirl-buns/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;In my last post, I made a &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pumpkin-skillet-coffee-cake/"&gt;pumpkin coffee cake&lt;/a&gt; that left me with a decent amount of opened pumpkin puree.
So, in an attempt to use it before it goes bad, I made &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/pumpkin-sweet-swirl-buns"&gt;pumpkin sweet swirl buns&lt;/a&gt; (similar to cinnamon buns).
I didn't have graham crackers, so I ground up a crunchy granola bar that aready had pimpkin seeds in it.
I also had to grind hazelnuts into a meal which is a bit tricky not to turn into nut butter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This used almost all of the remaining puree which is great. 
It also let me use my stand mixer to knead the dough.
I'm glad for any chance to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I was afraid I didn't roll the dough tight enough to get a good swirl.
However, the overnight proof in the fridge filled in the gaps.
I also made a cream cheese frosting by whipping cream cheese, lemon juice, vanilla extract, and powdered sugar together.
You can add a little bit of water to thin it out to your desired consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The buns were really good!
They were perfectly fluffy, a nice shade of orange, and the hazelnut filling was a perfect match for the spices.
My only (minor) complaint is that the pumpkin flavor was not strong enough.
I think the best takeaway is to try other fillings for cinnamon rolls.
The dough is just a fluffy, yeasty, buttery vehicle for the filling.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>hazelnut</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>pumpkin</category><category>Serious Eats</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pumpkin-sweet-swirl-buns/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 23:19:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pumpkin Skillet Coffee Cake</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pumpkin-skillet-coffee-cake/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;On occasion I will scour the internet for recipes to use up an indegredient I have too much of (see the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/pantry-raid/"&gt; pantry raid&lt;/a&gt; tag).
This time I was looking for old-fashioned oatmeal recipes, but it led me to another unused ingredient, pureed pumpkin.
I originally bought it when I was experimenting with a low-carb diet and didn't really like it in less sweet applications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serendipitously, a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/pumpkin-skillet-coffeecake-with-streusel-topping"&gt;pumpkin skillet coffee cake with oatmeal streusel&lt;/a&gt; could use both of these ingredients.
I really liked this cake, especially the texture that the white chocolate adds.
I didn't have any pecans, so I replaced them with some walnuts and pepitas (green pumpkin seeds).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this only used a fraction of each ingredient.
It didn't even use the whole can of pureed pumpkin that I opened.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cake</category><category>coffee</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>pumpkin</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>skillet</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/pumpkin-skillet-coffee-cake/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 14:51:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Watermelon Gazpacho</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/watermelon-gazpacho/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;The Independence Day gathering that I brought the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/practical-baked-alaska/"&gt;Baked Alaska&lt;/a&gt; to was a potluck.
The host made a really good watermelon, spinach, parmesan, and Balsamic vinagrette salad.
The watermelon they bought was &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt;, so they sent me home with half of it.
I found a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/watermelon-gazpacho-with-calabrian-chili-crema"&gt;watermelon gazpacho recipe&lt;/a&gt; to try to use it all up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn't find Calabrian chilis, so I just used some serranos.
I also found that it needed much more vinegar than the recipe called for.
Actually, it was quite hard to season the fresh soup, probably because it was cold and the flavors needed to mingle.
It turned out really well after resting in the fridge though.
This made me really appreciate the spicy watermelon combo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have way too much frozen watermelon leftover though...&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>gazpacho</category><category>pantry raid</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soup</category><category>watermelon</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/watermelon-gazpacho/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 01:30:21 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>