<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food (Posts about soup)</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/categories/soup.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:matt@manderscience.com"&gt;Matt Anderson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:50:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Watermelon Gazpacho</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/watermelon-gazpacho/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;The Independence Day gathering that I brought the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/practical-baked-alaska/"&gt;Baked Alaska&lt;/a&gt; to was a potluck.
The host made a really good watermelon, spinach, parmesan, and Balsamic vinagrette salad.
The watermelon they bought was &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt;, so they sent me home with half of it.
I found a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/watermelon-gazpacho-with-calabrian-chili-crema"&gt;watermelon gazpacho recipe&lt;/a&gt; to try to use it all up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn't find Calabrian chilis, so I just used some serranos.
I also found that it needed much more vinegar than the recipe called for.
Actually, it was quite hard to season the fresh soup, probably because it was cold and the flavors needed to mingle.
It turned out really well after resting in the fridge though.
This made me really appreciate the spicy watermelon combo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have way too much frozen watermelon leftover though...&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>gazpacho</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soup</category><category>watermelon</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/watermelon-gazpacho/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 01:30:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Masa Ball Soup and Champurrado</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/masa-ball-soup-and-champurrado/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;When I was researching the &lt;a href="https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/schmaltz-garlic-confit-and-matzo-ball-soup/"&gt;matzo ball soup&lt;/a&gt;, I came across something amusing: &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/how-to-make-masa-ball-soup-mexican-jewish-matzo-corn"&gt;Masa ball soup&lt;/a&gt;.
It's a Mexican take on the original dish. 
Both are essentially dumplings in chicken soup.
The dumplings here are made of masa, a specially treated corn flour used in tortillas, tamales, etc.
The last minor differences are using squash and cilantro instead of carrots and dill.
It's those changes that give the dish a Mexican flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The masa ball dough was pretty loose which made me fear that the balls would disintegrate while cooking.
Fortunately, they stayed together despite being a bit deformed.
Overall, this was the best tasting pun I've eaten, but I prefer the original a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I had the masa flour out, I decided to try making &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/champurrado-mexican-hot-chocolate-corn-drink-recipe"&gt;champurrado&lt;/a&gt;, a thickened hot chocolate drink.
I felt like the recipe was a bit lacking, so I added some cayenne, cumin, and coriander.
It was pretty good, but not the right time of year for hot chocolate.
One plus is that it sets up as a pudding when cooled which fit the season better.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>champurrado</category><category>chocolate</category><category>masa</category><category>matzo</category><category>pudding</category><category>pun</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soup</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/masa-ball-soup-and-champurrado/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 22:32:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Squash and Miso Soup From the Pantry</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/squash-and-miso-soup-from-the-pantry/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/miso-squash-soup-recipe"&gt;Miso-Squash Soup With Sesame-Ginger Apples&lt;/a&gt;, but I couldn't find all the ingredients.
In particular, I couldn't find bonito flakes at the normal place.
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Katsuobushi"&gt;Bonito flakes (katsuobushi)&lt;/a&gt; are simmered, smoked and fermented skipjack tuna.
They give dashi (kombu + katsuobushi), a japanese fish stock which is the base of miso soup, a smoky/meaty flavor.
I couldn't even find it (or instant dashi for that matter!) in the biggest Asian market in my city.
So, I had to improvise a bit.
A while ago, I was really into making different kinds of stocks.
I had frozen quarts of a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/hearty-vegetable-stock-vegan-recipe"&gt;vegan stock&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/fish-stock-fumet-recipe"&gt;French fish stock (fumet)&lt;/a&gt;.
I decided to replace the dashi with a combination of these two stocks because the vegan stock included kombu and dried mushrooms while the fumet was the only fishy stock I had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I boosted the fish flavor with some anchovy paste that I normally use in Italian dishes.
I also used two acorn squash instead of the butternut asked for in the recipe.
I like acorn squash because you can eat the thinner skin once cooked and they work very well in braised dishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like this dish because it reminds me of fall with the squash and apples, but still has a distinct flavor from the Asian ingredients.
Emptying my older pantry items is a big plus as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>acorn</category><category>apple</category><category>bonito</category><category>dashi</category><category>fish</category><category>fumet</category><category>katsuobushi</category><category>miso</category><category>pantry</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soup</category><category>squash</category><category>stock</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/squash-and-miso-soup-from-the-pantry/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:05:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Schmaltz, Garlic Confit, and Matzo Ball Soup</title><link>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/schmaltz-garlic-confit-and-matzo-ball-soup/</link><dc:creator>Matt Anderson</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;As previously mentioned, I like to buy whole chickens, break them down my self, and use the carcasses to make homemade stock.
However, this means I also have a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of chicken skin saved up as well.
I had 3 quart bags filled with skin and decided something needed to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the only thing I can really think to do with lots of chicken skin is to render out the fat, otherwise known as schmaltz.
Making schmaltz is pretty easy, just combine the skin with some water to start the rendering process and continue to cook until the fat is all rendered out.
I chopped the skin into smaller pieces to aid the rendering and was the most time consuming part.
Optionally, you can add some diced onion near the end to add some flavor. 
I ended up getting 1.5 pints of schmaltz from all that skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I made was confit garlic.
I packed a bunch of garlic cloves in a mason jar with the schmaltz and cooked it with an immersion circulator (sous vide) at 190F until lightly golden brown (about 6 hours).
The garlic cloves turn jammy and can be used as a savory spread.
I took it to a family gathering and added it to mashed potatos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I made was &lt;a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/the-best-matzo-balls-recipe"&gt;Matzo Ball Soup&lt;/a&gt; with some homemade stock and off the shelf matzo meal.
The schmaltz is added to the matzo balls for tenderness and flavor.
It reminded me of a chicken noodle soup with dumplings instead of noodles.
I also added extra dill because it's one of my favorite herbs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>carrot</category><category>chicken</category><category>confit</category><category>dill</category><category>fat</category><category>garlic</category><category>matzo</category><category>pantry-raid</category><category>schmaltz</category><category>Serious Eats</category><category>soup</category><guid>https://maxb2.github.io/food/posts/schmaltz-garlic-confit-and-matzo-ball-soup/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 02:12:48 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>